<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>New datasets from opendata.cityofnewyork.us</title><link>https://github.com/palewire/nyc-open-data-monitor</link><description>The latest datasets posted to New York City's data portal</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 00:17:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Parking Violations Issued - Fiscal Year 2023</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/869v-vr48</link><description>This dataset provides data on Parking Violations Issued between July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023. In New York City, the fiscal year begins on July 1st of one calendar year and ends on June 30th of the following calendar year. Click here to find out more about the NYC Fiscal Year. Parking Violations Issuance datasets contain violations issued during the respective fiscal year. The Issuance datasets are not updated to reflect violation status, the information only represents the violation(s) at the time they are issued. Since appearing on an issuance dataset, a violation may have been paid, dismissed via a hearing, statutorily expired, or had other changes to its status. To see the current status of outstanding parking violations, please look at the Open Parking &amp; Camera Violations dataset. &lt;b&gt;NOTE:&lt;/b&gt; This dataset includes the records from the first month of FY2024. You may find all of the Parking Violations Issued since fiscal year 2014 in this dataset collection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">869v-vr48</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 14:55:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxi and For Hire Vehicle (FHV) Relief Stands (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/udk9-t2yf</link><description>This data details the location of the Taxi and For Hire Vehicle(FHV) stands and the number of spaces provided. Taxi and FHV relief stands allow drivers to park their vehicles for up to one hour. This gives drivers the opportunity to leave their vehicles and take care of personal needs. &lt;b&gt;TNOTE:&lt;/b&gt; Taxi and FHV relief stands should not be confused with taxi stands. Taxi stands allow drivers to wait in their cars to pick up passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">udk9-t2yf</guid><category>Transportation</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 19:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DOB Safety Violations</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/855j-jady</link><description>This data set includes violations issued on devices through the New York City Department of Buildings' DOB NOW: Safety Violations module. The data is collected because the Department of Buildings tracks violation issuance and related information. This data include items such as violations number, violations type, violation issuance data, and BIN.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">855j-jady</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 16:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Open Streets Locations Map</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/6vys-sfk5</link><description>New York City's Open Streets program transforms streets into public spaces open to all. These public spaces allows a variety of activities including education and cultural programming as well as building communities. For more information please visit: https://www.nyc.gov/html/dot/html/pedestrians/openstreets.shtml Please note: there may be a delay in updates to the Open Data files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6vys-sfk5</guid><category>Health</category><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 19:18:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mayor's Management Report Spending and Budget</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/2jrp-puwz</link><description>Contains Spending and Budget information for City agencies, as reported in the Mayoral Management Report (MMR).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2jrp-puwz</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:06:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mayor's Management Report Agency Resources</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/4qmi-txnk</link><description>Includes NYC agency resources from the Mayor's Management Report (MMR), such as expenditures (includes all funds), personnel, revenue and paid overtime. This data is an overview of the financial and workforce resources used by an agency and the planned resources available to the agency in a given reporting fiscal year or future fiscal years. The MMR, archived reports, and additional information is available at: https://www1.nyc.gov/site/operations/performance/mmr.page and https://dmmr.nyc.gov/</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4qmi-txnk</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:03:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Elevation and Subgrade (BES) - Map</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/nmzg-6q5g</link><description>The Building Elevation and Subgrade data contains New York City building centroids derived from the Department of Building's (DOB) February 26th, 2022 building footprint dataset. Each record contains a grade and first floor measurement for each building (recorded as feet above sea-level in the NADV88 vertical datum) and indicates if subgrade space exists. DCP contracted with an external data vendor to generate a single point, or centroid, that represented the location of the center of every building recorded in the DOB dataset. The dataset excluded the footprints of small accessory buildings such as sheds. Each row within the dataset represents one building centroid, and records the X and Y coordinates of that centroid in the NAD 1983 coordinate system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">nmzg-6q5g</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2023 Open Data Plan: Civic Engagement Activities</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/xw44-6wmw</link><description>Released as a part of the 2023 Open Data Plan, this is a list of civic engagement activities reported by city agencies for the purpose of providing context, spreading awareness and increasing the use of public city data. Details include activity descriptions, date of completion and resource links to further information on the reported activity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">xw44-6wmw</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 21:27:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Elevation and Subgrade (BES)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/bsin-59hv</link><description>The Building Elevation and Subgrade data contains New York City building centroids derived from the Department of Building's (DOB) February 26th, 2022 building footprint dataset. Each record contains a grade and first floor measurement for each building (recorded as feet above sea-level in the NADV88 vertical datum) and indicates if subgrade space exists. DCP contracted with an external data vendor to generate a single point, or centroid, that represented the location of the center of every building recorded in the DOB dataset. The dataset excluded the footprints of small accessory buildings such as sheds. Each row within the dataset represents one building centroid, and records the X and Y coordinates of that centroid in the NAD 1983 coordinate system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bsin-59hv</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2023 Open Data Plan: Removals</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/bhst-9d3f</link><description>The list of the datasets that were removed from the Open Data Plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bhst-9d3f</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 23:33:38 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2023 Open Data Plan: FOIL Datasets</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/93kn-fhqt</link><description>The collection of datasets identified via FOIL reporting and their respective release statuses as a part of the 2023 Open Data Plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93kn-fhqt</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 17:42:23 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2023 Open Data Plan: Future Releases</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/59qh-uc8y</link><description>The collection of datasets set to be released on the Open Data Portal, according to the 2023 Open Data Plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59qh-uc8y</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 17:26:03 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2023 Open Data Plan: FOIL Metrics</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/33mm-wzxh</link><description>Various FOIL reporting metrics as part of the 2023 Open Data Compliance Plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33mm-wzxh</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 16:55:54 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2023 Open Data Plan: Website Data</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/rzp5-dkki</link><description>Data on public websites maintained by or on behalf of the city agencies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">rzp5-dkki</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 15:44:31 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Preliminary Mayor's Management Report Agency Resources</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/nvzu-6t9y</link><description>Includes NYC agency resources from the Preliminary Mayor's Management Report (PMMR), such as expenditures (includes all funds), personnel, revenue and paid overtime. This data is an overview of the financial and workforce resources used by an agency and the planned resources available to the agency in a given reporting fiscal year or future fiscal years. The PMMR, archived reports, and additional information is available at: https://www1.nyc.gov/site/operations/performance/mmr.page and https://dmmr.nyc.gov/</description><guid isPermaLink="false">nvzu-6t9y</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:21:02 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Preliminary Mayor's Management Report Spending and Budget</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/w4ne-9ea9</link><description>Contains Spending and Budget information for City agencies, as reported in the Preliminary Mayoral Management Report (PMMR).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">w4ne-9ea9</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:03:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Citywide Public Computer Centers</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/sejx-2gn3</link><description>A public computing center (“PCC”) is a facility offering computers with internet access. It may also offer other devices, services, and digital literacy and digital skills programming, for example. A PCC may be funded in whole, or in part, with public dollars in order to provide a public service (i.e., access to digital inclusion resources). Some PCCs are open to the general public while others may have membership criteria such as age. As an inventory, and as feasible, OTI’s purpose was to collect, count, and map where and how the City supports this kind of public access to the internet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">sejx-2gn3</guid><category>Social Services</category><pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2023 13:26:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dewatered Solids and Biosolids Allocations per Biosolids Management Practice Site</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/95kh-h6zc</link><description>This dataset contains annual allocations of dewatered solids or biosolids from a specific dewatering facility to a specific management practice site in dry metric tons. 'Dewatered solids' are the solids remaining in digested sludge after removal of water in a dewatering facility. 'Biosolids', per the US Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), is treated sewage sludge that meets the EPA pollutant, pathogen &amp; vector attraction requirements for land application and surface disposal, and the DEP has certified it with the EPA as such. Biosolids in this case are also dewatered. Depending on the material being managed (i.e., dewatered solids or biosolids), a 'management practice site' may be one of the following: 1) a third party vendor treatment facility (e.g., composting, dryer, alkaline treatment) that converts the dewatered solids into biosolids for beneficial reuse in various land application practices (e.g., agricultural land application, reclamation site application) or for distribution/marketing as a soil amendment or fertilizer; 2) a direct land application site for agricultural use (typically a farm); or 3) a landfill. The dataset includes the pathogen (disease-causing organism) reduction and vector (an animal capable of transmitting disease such as flies or rodents) attraction reduction options employed as part of the treatment and the type of biosolids class produced, if applicable. There are different biosolids class types, each having specified treatment requirements for pollutants, pathogens and vector attraction reduction, as well as general requirements and management practices, For more information regarding biosolids compliance, treatment, uses and class types please refer to: &lt;a href="https://www.epa.gov/biosolids"&gt;https://www.epa.gov/biosolids&lt;/a&gt;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95kh-h6zc</guid><category>Environment</category><pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 13:17:14 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxi and For Hire Vehicle (FHV) Relief Stands</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/vqu8-xef9</link><description>This data details the location of the Taxi and For Hire Vehicle(FHV) stands and the number of spaces provided. Taxi and FHV relief stands allow drivers to park their vehicles for up to one hour. This gives drivers the opportunity to leave their vehicles and take care of personal needs. &lt;b&gt;TNOTE:&lt;/b&gt; Taxi and FHV relief stands should not be confused with taxi stands. Taxi stands allow drivers to wait in their cars to pick up passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">vqu8-xef9</guid><category>Transportation</category><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 17:52:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NYC Parks Spray Showers Map</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/im58-6hb9</link><description>This dataset provides the location of spray showers under the jurisdiction of NYC Parks. For more information about spray showers, visit https://www.nycgovparks.org/facilities/sprayshowers Data Dictionary: https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1q-MxMTrsE46Vdy-vea5lxCok8xD3Nd4zIvEI2KYgm08/edit?usp=sharing</description><guid isPermaLink="false">im58-6hb9</guid><category>Recreation</category><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 19:10:04 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>