<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>New datasets from opendata.cityofnewyork.us</title><link>https://github.com/palewire/nyc-open-data-monitor</link><description>The latest datasets posted to New York City's data portal</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 12:15:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Off-Year and Special Elections Public Matching Fund Payments</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/7f4s-uwi7</link><description>This dataset contains public matching funds payments to a campaign during an off-year or special election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f4s-uwi7</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 20:09:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Off-Year and Special Elections Financial Analysis</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/ups9-zwkm</link><description>This dataset contains a financial summary of each campaign during an off-year or special election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ups9-zwkm</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 19:51:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital Projects Dashboard - Budget and Spend by Fiscal Year</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/gyhf-rsr3</link><description>All major capital infrastructure projects with a committed budget and spend by fiscal year. Financial information and agency schedule details for each project are joined via FMS ID. Only projects in the design phase or later have project schedules displayed. Note: Each row is uniquely identified by its Financial Management Service (FMS) ID. FMS ID is the unique ID that OMB uses for the FMS (Financial Information System). This ID can be universally joined with any OMB dataset that has the same field. The Capital Projects Dashboard is the result of joining OMB’s fiscal data with the agency’s schedule data. FMS IDs and agency projects don't always have a one-to-one relationship (ie. one project schedule may correlate to multiple FMS IDs, and one FMS may correct to multiple projects with different schedules).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">gyhf-rsr3</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 19:32:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital Projects Dashboard - Budget and Schedule</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/fb86-vt7u</link><description>All major capital infrastructure projects with a committed budget. Financial information and agency schedule details for each project are joined via FMS ID. Only projects in the design phase or later have project schedules displayed. Note: Each row is uniquely identified by its Financial Management Service (FMS) ID. FMS ID is the unique ID that OMB uses for the FMS (Financial Information System). This ID can be universally joined with any OMB dataset that has the same field. The Capital Projects Dashboard is the result of joining OMB’s fiscal data with the agency’s schedule data. FMS IDs and agency projects don't always have a one-to-one relationship (i.e., one project schedule may correlate to multiple FMS IDs, and one FMS may correct to multiple projects with different schedules).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb86-vt7u</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 19:18:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unique Businesses that received EO50 certificate of approval from SBS</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/5vi6-xdpy</link><description>List of Businesses that have successfully complied with EO50 Requirements and received EO50 certificate of approval from SBS. Executive Order No. 50 was established in 1980 during Mayor Koch's tenure. It mandates that all contractors adhere to equal employment principles, explicitly prohibiting discriminatory hiring practices. This order safeguards individuals from discrimination based on ten protected categories: race, sex, creed, age, color, disability, national origin, marital status, sexual orientation, and citizenship status. For additional information, please visit our website at &lt;a href="https://www.nyc.gov/site/sbs/businesses/contract-compliance.page"&gt;https://www.nyc.gov/site/sbs/businesses/contract-compliance.page&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5vi6-xdpy</guid><category>Business</category><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 19:17:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark and Historic District Building Database (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/7rcw-iixi</link><description>Provides information on buildings and structures within designated historic districts and individual landmark sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7rcw-iixi</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark and Historic District Building Database</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/gpmc-yuvp</link><description>Provides information on buildings and structures within designated historic districts and individual landmark sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">gpmc-yuvp</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:03:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark Sites (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/xut8-7f42</link><description>This dataset contains site boundaries for all designated individual landmarks as well as administrative information such as site boundary description and designation date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">xut8-7f42</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 19:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark Sites</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/buis-pvji</link><description>This dataset contains site boundaries for all designated individual landmarks as well as administrative information such as site boundary description and designation date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">buis-pvji</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 19:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scenic Landmarks (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/rruq-hv9m</link><description>Provides boundary information regarding all scenic landmarks that have been calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">rruq-hv9m</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:40:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scenic Landmarks</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/qexa-qpj6</link><description>Provides boundary information regarding all scenic landmarks that have been calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">qexa-qpj6</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic Districts (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/ny8p-kkj4</link><description>Provides information regarding all historic districts that have calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued, as well as many proposed districts in the study area phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ny8p-kkj4</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic Districts</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/skyk-mpzq</link><description>Provides information regarding all historic districts that have calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued, as well as many proposed districts in the study area phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">skyk-mpzq</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 17:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Local Law 83 - City Agency Advertising Spend</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/n56u-3hzv</link><description>Per Local Law 83 of 2021, the Mayor's Office of Ethnic and Community Media is required to report annually on each agency's full advertising spend across all media categories, including ethnic and community (ECM), mainstream, out-of-home, social media, etc. This dataset reflects the raw data that MOECM received from City Agencies on their annual advertising spend. For more information, please visit the &lt;a href="https://www.nyc.gov/site/ethnicmedia/index.page"&gt;MOECM website&lt;/a&gt;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">n56u-3hzv</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 17:21:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parking Violations Issued - Fiscal Year 2023</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/869v-vr48</link><description>This dataset provides data on Parking Violations Issued between July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023. In New York City, the fiscal year begins on July 1st of one calendar year and ends on June 30th of the following calendar year. Click here to find out more about the NYC Fiscal Year. Parking Violations Issuance datasets contain violations issued during the respective fiscal year. The Issuance datasets are not updated to reflect violation status, the information only represents the violation(s) at the time they are issued. Since appearing on an issuance dataset, a violation may have been paid, dismissed via a hearing, statutorily expired, or had other changes to its status. To see the current status of outstanding parking violations, please look at the Open Parking &amp; Camera Violations dataset. &lt;b&gt;NOTE:&lt;/b&gt; This dataset includes the records from the first month of FY2024. You may find all of the Parking Violations Issued since fiscal year 2014 in this dataset collection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">869v-vr48</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 14:55:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PMMR Performance Indicators FY2013-15 (Historical Data)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/n6uf-ruxa</link><description>This data contains all indicator data from the PY13-FY15 Preliminary Mayor's Management Reports (meaning all data from performance indicators related to each agency's work, not including budgeting and agency resource data). The full text of the FY13-15 PMMRs, archived reports, and additional information is available at https://www1.nyc.gov/site/operations/performance/mmr.page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">n6uf-ruxa</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2022 High Volume FHV Trip Records</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/g6pj-fsah</link><description>These records are generated from the trip record submissions made by High Volume For-Hire Vehicle (FHV) bases. On August 14, 2018, Mayor de Blasio signed Local Law 149 of 2018, creating a new license category for TLC-licensed FHV businesses that currently dispatch or plan to dispatch more than 10,000 FHV trips in New York City per day under a single brand, trade, or operating name, referred to as High-Volume For-Hire Services (HVFHS). This law went into effect on Feb 1, 2019. Each row represents a single trip in a FHV dispatched by a high volume base. The trip records include fields capturing the high volume license number, the pickup and drop-off date, time, and taxi zone location ID, which correspond with the NYC Taxi Zones open dataset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">g6pj-fsah</guid><category>Transportation</category><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 15:11:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxi and For Hire Vehicle (FHV) Relief Stands (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/udk9-t2yf</link><description>This data details the location of the Taxi and For Hire Vehicle(FHV) stands and the number of spaces provided. Taxi and FHV relief stands allow drivers to park their vehicles for up to one hour. This gives drivers the opportunity to leave their vehicles and take care of personal needs. &lt;b&gt;TNOTE:&lt;/b&gt; Taxi and FHV relief stands should not be confused with taxi stands. Taxi stands allow drivers to wait in their cars to pick up passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">udk9-t2yf</guid><category>Transportation</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 19:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Publicly Owned Waterfront</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/jr73-mxkz</link><description>City, State, and Federally owned public parks and facilities that provide waterfront parkland and open space for public enjoyment, as shown on the NYC DCP Waterfront Access Map (WAM) - waterfrontaccess.planning.nyc.gov.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">jr73-mxkz</guid><category>Recreation</category><pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 21:09:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2021 High Volume FHV Trip Records</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/5ufr-wvc5</link><description>These records are generated from the trip record submissions made by High Volume For-Hire Vehicle (FHV) bases. On August 14, 2018, Mayor de Blasio signed Local Law 149 of 2018, creating a new license category for TLC-licensed FHV businesses that currently dispatch or plan to dispatch more than 10,000 FHV trips in New York City per day under a single brand, trade, or operating name, referred to as High-Volume For-Hire Services (HVFHS). This law went into effect on Feb 1, 2019. Each row represents a single trip in a FHV dispatched by a high volume base. The trip records include fields capturing the high volume license number, the pickup and drop-off date, time, and taxi zone location ID, which correspond with the NYC Taxi Zones open dataset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ufr-wvc5</guid><category>Transportation</category><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 15:18:34 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>