<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>New datasets from opendata.cityofnewyork.us</title><link>https://github.com/palewire/nyc-open-data-monitor</link><description>The latest datasets posted to New York City's data portal</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:20:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Individual Landmark and Historic District Building Database (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/7rcw-iixi</link><description>Provides information on buildings and structures within designated historic districts and individual landmark sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7rcw-iixi</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark and Historic District Building Database</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/gpmc-yuvp</link><description>Provides information on buildings and structures within designated historic districts and individual landmark sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">gpmc-yuvp</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:03:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark Sites (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/xut8-7f42</link><description>This dataset contains site boundaries for all designated individual landmarks as well as administrative information such as site boundary description and designation date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">xut8-7f42</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 19:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark Sites</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/buis-pvji</link><description>This dataset contains site boundaries for all designated individual landmarks as well as administrative information such as site boundary description and designation date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">buis-pvji</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 19:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scenic Landmarks (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/rruq-hv9m</link><description>Provides boundary information regarding all scenic landmarks that have been calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">rruq-hv9m</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:40:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scenic Landmarks</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/qexa-qpj6</link><description>Provides boundary information regarding all scenic landmarks that have been calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">qexa-qpj6</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic Districts (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/ny8p-kkj4</link><description>Provides information regarding all historic districts that have calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued, as well as many proposed districts in the study area phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ny8p-kkj4</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:14:35 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Historic Districts</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/skyk-mpzq</link><description>Provides information regarding all historic districts that have calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued, as well as many proposed districts in the study area phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">skyk-mpzq</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 17:53:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Local Law 83 - City Agency Advertising Spend</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/n56u-3hzv</link><description>Per Local Law 83 of 2021, the Mayor's Office of Ethnic and Community Media is required to report annually on each agency's full advertising spend across all media categories, including ethnic and community (ECM), mainstream, out-of-home, social media, etc. This dataset reflects the raw data that MOECM received from City Agencies on their annual advertising spend. For more information, please visit the &lt;a href="https://www.nyc.gov/site/ethnicmedia/index.page"&gt;MOECM website&lt;/a&gt;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">n56u-3hzv</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 17:21:13 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parking Violations Issued - Fiscal Year 2023</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/869v-vr48</link><description>This dataset provides data on Parking Violations Issued between July 1, 2022 to June 30, 2023. In New York City, the fiscal year begins on July 1st of one calendar year and ends on June 30th of the following calendar year. Click here to find out more about the NYC Fiscal Year. Parking Violations Issuance datasets contain violations issued during the respective fiscal year. The Issuance datasets are not updated to reflect violation status, the information only represents the violation(s) at the time they are issued. Since appearing on an issuance dataset, a violation may have been paid, dismissed via a hearing, statutorily expired, or had other changes to its status. To see the current status of outstanding parking violations, please look at the Open Parking &amp; Camera Violations dataset. &lt;b&gt;NOTE:&lt;/b&gt; This dataset includes the records from the first month of FY2024. You may find all of the Parking Violations Issued since fiscal year 2014 in this dataset collection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">869v-vr48</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 14:55:34 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PMMR Performance Indicators FY2013-15 (Historical Data)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/n6uf-ruxa</link><description>This data contains all indicator data from the PY13-FY15 Preliminary Mayor's Management Reports (meaning all data from performance indicators related to each agency's work, not including budgeting and agency resource data). The full text of the FY13-15 PMMRs, archived reports, and additional information is available at https://www1.nyc.gov/site/operations/performance/mmr.page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">n6uf-ruxa</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:10:53 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taxi and For Hire Vehicle (FHV) Relief Stands (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/udk9-t2yf</link><description>This data details the location of the Taxi and For Hire Vehicle(FHV) stands and the number of spaces provided. Taxi and FHV relief stands allow drivers to park their vehicles for up to one hour. This gives drivers the opportunity to leave their vehicles and take care of personal needs. &lt;b&gt;TNOTE:&lt;/b&gt; Taxi and FHV relief stands should not be confused with taxi stands. Taxi stands allow drivers to wait in their cars to pick up passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">udk9-t2yf</guid><category>Transportation</category><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 19:11:50 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DOB Safety Violations</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/855j-jady</link><description>This data set includes violations issued on devices through the New York City Department of Buildings' DOB NOW: Safety Violations module. The data is collected because the Department of Buildings tracks violation issuance and related information. This data include items such as violations number, violations type, violation issuance data, and BIN.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">855j-jady</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 16:22:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Open Streets Locations Map</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/6vys-sfk5</link><description>New York City's Open Streets program transforms streets into public spaces open to all. These public spaces allows a variety of activities including education and cultural programming as well as building communities. For more information please visit: https://www.nyc.gov/html/dot/html/pedestrians/openstreets.shtml Please note: there may be a delay in updates to the Open Data files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6vys-sfk5</guid><category>Health</category><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 19:18:56 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HRA Facts, Programs and Services</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/np6w-pies</link><description>Monthly trend statistics about HRA programs including Cash Assistance, SNAP, Medicaid, Employment, and Special Services, from the Office of Performance Management and Data Analytics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">np6w-pies</guid><category>Social Services</category><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 18:53:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mayor's Management Report Spending and Budget</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/2jrp-puwz</link><description>Contains Spending and Budget information for City agencies, as reported in the Mayoral Management Report (MMR).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2jrp-puwz</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:06:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mayor's Management Report Agency Resources</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/4qmi-txnk</link><description>Includes NYC agency resources from the Mayor's Management Report (MMR), such as expenditures (includes all funds), personnel, revenue and paid overtime. This data is an overview of the financial and workforce resources used by an agency and the planned resources available to the agency in a given reporting fiscal year or future fiscal years. The MMR, archived reports, and additional information is available at: https://www1.nyc.gov/site/operations/performance/mmr.page and https://dmmr.nyc.gov/</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4qmi-txnk</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 17:03:49 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Elevation and Subgrade (BES) - Map</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/nmzg-6q5g</link><description>The Building Elevation and Subgrade data contains New York City building centroids derived from the Department of Building's (DOB) February 26th, 2022 building footprint dataset. Each record contains a grade and first floor measurement for each building (recorded as feet above sea-level in the NADV88 vertical datum) and indicates if subgrade space exists. DCP contracted with an external data vendor to generate a single point, or centroid, that represented the location of the center of every building recorded in the DOB dataset. The dataset excluded the footprints of small accessory buildings such as sheds. Each row within the dataset represents one building centroid, and records the X and Y coordinates of that centroid in the NAD 1983 coordinate system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">nmzg-6q5g</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 20:47:20 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>2023 Open Data Plan: Civic Engagement Activities</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/xw44-6wmw</link><description>Released as a part of the 2023 Open Data Plan, this is a list of civic engagement activities reported by city agencies for the purpose of providing context, spreading awareness and increasing the use of public city data. Details include activity descriptions, date of completion and resource links to further information on the reported activity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">xw44-6wmw</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 21:27:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Building Elevation and Subgrade (BES)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/bsin-59hv</link><description>The Building Elevation and Subgrade data contains New York City building centroids derived from the Department of Building's (DOB) February 26th, 2022 building footprint dataset. Each record contains a grade and first floor measurement for each building (recorded as feet above sea-level in the NADV88 vertical datum) and indicates if subgrade space exists. DCP contracted with an external data vendor to generate a single point, or centroid, that represented the location of the center of every building recorded in the DOB dataset. The dataset excluded the footprints of small accessory buildings such as sheds. Each row within the dataset represents one building centroid, and records the X and Y coordinates of that centroid in the NAD 1983 coordinate system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bsin-59hv</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 19:06:08 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>