<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>New datasets from opendata.cityofnewyork.us</title><link>https://github.com/palewire/nyc-open-data-monitor</link><description>The latest datasets posted to New York City's data portal</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:35:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>District Resource Statement (DRS)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/au2c-rs69</link><description>This dataset includes information regarding the population of individuals and households receiving SNAP, Cash Assistance, and/or Medicaid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">au2c-rs69</guid><category>Social Services</category><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 18:51:05 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NYCHA Public Housing Developments Map</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/npwq-dpkb</link><description>Locations of the public housing developments of the New York City Housing Authority as of January 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">npwq-dpkb</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:10:17 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NYCHA Public Housing Developments</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/phvi-damg</link><description>Locations of the public housing developments of the New York City Housing Authority as of January 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">phvi-damg</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 22:03:55 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New York City Climate Projections: Extreme Events and Sea Level Rise</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/38ps-fnsg</link><description>This report includes updated changes in extreme events (e.g., hot days, days with heavy rainfall, heat waves) for the 2030s, 2050s and 2080s; and sea level rise projections for the 2030s, 2050s, 2080s, 2100 and 2150 for the New York City region, based on those developed for the IPCC 6th Assessment report. The sea level rise projections are based on the CMIP6 models and SSP framework, and also incorporate advances in process understanding, improved and lengthened observational records, and improved ice-sheet modeling. The New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) started in 2009 and was codified in Local Law 42 of 2012 with a mandate to provide an authoritative and actionable source of scientific information on future climate change and its potential impacts. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) is the United Nations body for assessing the science related to climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38ps-fnsg</guid><category>Environment</category><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 20:14:37 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Public feedback on 311 request/complaint types</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/7ffd-6gs9</link><description>This dataset contains a listing of comments and requests from the public for the addition of a new or update to an existing NYC 311 service request/complaint type. This data is required to be published under Local Law 97 of 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ffd-6gs9</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 21:25:25 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New York City Climate Projections: Temperature and Precipitation</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/hmdk-eidg</link><description>Temperature and precipitation projections for NYC reported by the New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC). The New York City Panel on Climate Change (NPCC) started in 2009 and was codified in Local Law 42 of 2012 with a mandate to provide an authoritative and actionable source of scientific information on future climate change and its potential impacts. The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC) is the United Nations body for assessing the science related to climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">hmdk-eidg</guid><category>Environment</category><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 15:01:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cash Assistance Emergency Assistance Requests</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/5vgr-4tp3</link><description>Quarterly statistics about the Human Resources Administration’s Emergency Assistance Grants from the Department of Social Services Office of Performance Management and Data Analytics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5vgr-4tp3</guid><category>Social Services</category><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 15:50:58 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Neighborhood Development Areas Map</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/p57r-4v4f</link><description>This map contains the shape of each NDA and borough it is located in. As the designated Community Action Agency of New York City, DYCD administers the federal Community Services Block Grant (CSBG) program to combat poverty and provide emergency services to low-income people. In order to maximize the impact of the federal CSBG funding, DYCD targets funds to low-income communities, which it designates as Neighborhood Development Areas (NDAs). The NDA Initiative, through the Neighborhood Advisory Boards (NABs), fosters community-level engagement to ensure that residents have opportunities to contribute to change in their neighborhoods and that services address the most pressing needs of each community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">p57r-4v4f</guid><category>Social Services</category><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 16:49:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Neighborhood Development Areas</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/vd7c-qjsx</link><description>This dataset contains the shape of each Neighborhood Development Area (NDA) and borough it is located in. As the designated Community Action Agency of New York City, DYCD administers the federal Community Services Block Grant (CSBG) program to combat poverty and provide emergency services to low-income people. In order to maximize the impact of the federal CSBG funding, DYCD targets funds to low-income communities, which it designates as Neighborhood Development Areas (NDAs). The NDA Initiative, through the Neighborhood Advisory Boards (NABs), fosters community-level engagement to ensure that residents have opportunities to contribute to change in their neighborhoods and that services address the most pressing needs of each community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">vd7c-qjsx</guid><category>Social Services</category><pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 15:36:33 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Off-Year and Special Elections Public Matching Fund Payments</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/7f4s-uwi7</link><description>This dataset contains public matching funds payments to a campaign during an off-year or special election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f4s-uwi7</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 20:09:43 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Off-Year and Special Elections Financial Analysis</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/ups9-zwkm</link><description>This dataset contains a financial summary of each campaign during an off-year or special election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ups9-zwkm</guid><category>City Government</category><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 19:51:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital Projects Dashboard - Budget and Spend by Fiscal Year</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/gyhf-rsr3</link><description>All major capital infrastructure projects with a committed budget and spend by fiscal year. Financial information and agency schedule details for each project are joined via FMS ID. Only projects in the design phase or later have project schedules displayed. Note: Each row is uniquely identified by its Financial Management Service (FMS) ID. FMS ID is the unique ID that OMB uses for the FMS (Financial Information System). This ID can be universally joined with any OMB dataset that has the same field. The Capital Projects Dashboard is the result of joining OMB’s fiscal data with the agency’s schedule data. FMS IDs and agency projects don't always have a one-to-one relationship (ie. one project schedule may correlate to multiple FMS IDs, and one FMS may correct to multiple projects with different schedules).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">gyhf-rsr3</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 19:32:30 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital Projects Dashboard - Budget and Schedule</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/fb86-vt7u</link><description>All major capital infrastructure projects with a committed budget. Financial information and agency schedule details for each project are joined via FMS ID. Only projects in the design phase or later have project schedules displayed. Note: Each row is uniquely identified by its Financial Management Service (FMS) ID. FMS ID is the unique ID that OMB uses for the FMS (Financial Information System). This ID can be universally joined with any OMB dataset that has the same field. The Capital Projects Dashboard is the result of joining OMB’s fiscal data with the agency’s schedule data. FMS IDs and agency projects don't always have a one-to-one relationship (i.e., one project schedule may correlate to multiple FMS IDs, and one FMS may correct to multiple projects with different schedules).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb86-vt7u</guid><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 19:18:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Unique Businesses that received EO50 certificate of approval from SBS</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/5vi6-xdpy</link><description>List of Businesses that have successfully complied with EO50 Requirements and received EO50 certificate of approval from SBS. Executive Order No. 50 was established in 1980 during Mayor Koch's tenure. It mandates that all contractors adhere to equal employment principles, explicitly prohibiting discriminatory hiring practices. This order safeguards individuals from discrimination based on ten protected categories: race, sex, creed, age, color, disability, national origin, marital status, sexual orientation, and citizenship status. For additional information, please visit our website at &lt;a href="https://www.nyc.gov/site/sbs/businesses/contract-compliance.page"&gt;https://www.nyc.gov/site/sbs/businesses/contract-compliance.page&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5vi6-xdpy</guid><category>Business</category><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 19:17:19 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark and Historic District Building Database (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/7rcw-iixi</link><description>Provides information on buildings and structures within designated historic districts and individual landmark sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7rcw-iixi</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:14:22 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark and Historic District Building Database</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/gpmc-yuvp</link><description>Provides information on buildings and structures within designated historic districts and individual landmark sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">gpmc-yuvp</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:03:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark Sites (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/xut8-7f42</link><description>This dataset contains site boundaries for all designated individual landmarks as well as administrative information such as site boundary description and designation date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">xut8-7f42</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 19:57:44 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Individual Landmark Sites</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/buis-pvji</link><description>This dataset contains site boundaries for all designated individual landmarks as well as administrative information such as site boundary description and designation date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">buis-pvji</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 19:38:27 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scenic Landmarks (Map)</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/rruq-hv9m</link><description>Provides boundary information regarding all scenic landmarks that have been calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">rruq-hv9m</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:40:32 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Scenic Landmarks</title><link>https://data.cityofnewyork.us/d/qexa-qpj6</link><description>Provides boundary information regarding all scenic landmarks that have been calendared, heard, or designated by the Landmarks Preservation Commission, or for which an LP number has been issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">qexa-qpj6</guid><category>Housing &amp; Development</category><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:27:59 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>